MARIO IMPRONTA

Rua Oscar Pereira da Silva 102 ap 74 Itaim Bibi - São Paulo - SP - Brazil mario.impronta@gmail.com https://br.linkedin.com/in/mario-impronta-7572154

Systems engineer, integrator & developer. Experienced Linux and Unix systems programmer and administrator. Cloud/virtualization experience (Amazon/Xen/VMware/Google Cloud). Front-end developer (PHP and Javascript). Back-end developer: C/C++ and Shell scripting specialist; skilled ETL programmer in Talend Java/Perl. Experienced low level and embedded systems programmer. Programming languages and Unix instructor. Hardware/Electronics background. Financial and Risk Management knowledge. Public university, private telecomm and financial services experience, for Brazilian, British and Canadian companies. Native Portuguese and fluent English speaker.

Professional Experience

MI Consultoria e Treinamento, São Paulo, Brazil M&M Tecnologia Ltda, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Owner - Consulting Services - 2021+)

(Owner - Consulting Services - 2003-2021)

Decision Tecnologia da Informação Ltda, São Paulo, Brazil Systems Engineer & Developer

(Retail Payment Systems) 2022

As an engineer: creating virtual environments at Google Cloud for validation of TP products, for client *Diebold-Nixdorf*. As a developer: C code analysis/fixing, same client. Environments: GC, RedHat 7, gcc.

TO Brasil Consultoria em TI Ltda, São Paulo, Brazil Developer

(Payment Systems Software)

2021

C/C++ development, code vulnerability analysis (Fortify), for client *Fiserv / Software Express*. Environments and tools: Fortify, FortifyOnDemand, Visual Studio, Visual C++, Windows 10.

ACI Worldwide Inc., São Paulo, Brazil

(Payment Systems Software)

Consultant

2021

Performing UPF (Universal Payments Framework) monitoring&configuration, for client Santander GetNet.

Solarview Tecnologia Ltda, Belo Horizonte, Brazil Developer

(Solar Energy Integration Software) 2018,2021

Creation of Javascript/NodeJS robots-crawlers to collect solar energy data from providers.

IDid Tecnologia Ltda, São Paulo, Brazil

(Payment Systems Software)

Developer

2021

Python development and DevOps (setting up Amazon AWS servers, Jenkins CI/CD and Mmock/Golang).

Riskgrid Technologies Inc., Toronto, Canada Systems Engineer, Developer and Integrator

(Financial Risk Management Software)

As an engineer: in charge of designing / setting up / integrating / managing all production, development and network environments on the brazilian side; as a developer/integrator: coding and customization of all data collectors/ETL and web services for Brazilian market data & fund analysis products (MarketWatch and FundWatch). System environments: CentOS and Windows Server (on Amazon EC2), Red Hat Enterprise & Fedora. Software environments: Talend, C/C++, Perl, Shell (bash), Apache, mySql and Oracle databases.

Brit Services Ltd., São Paulo, Brazil and London, UK (Financial Risk Management Software) **Systems Engineer and Developer**

As an engineer: in charge of designing and maintaining brazilian office infra-structure; as a developer: integration/systems C/AIX programming on client site (HSBC). System envs: CentOS & Fedora, Windows, AIX. Software envs: C/C++, Shell (ksh), Sybase.

Algorithmics Inc. (now SS&C), Toronto, Canada (Financial Risk Management Software) **Network/Systems Administrator and Integrator**

As an administrator: in charge of planning / setting up / integrating / managing all production, development and network environments for the brazilian chapter; as a developer/integrator: designing and coding data collecting & integration solutions for the Market Server data product. System environments: Solaris 9/8/2.6 for Sparc, Red Hat 7, Mandriva 2005, Windows Server 2003 and 2000. Software environments: C/C++, Perl, Shell (bash), Java, JBoss/Tomcat servers, MSSQL/Firebird/Oracle 9 databases.

APPI Informática Ltda (now Muxi), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Telecom Integration Solutions) Telecom Support Analyst and Embedded System Developer 1998-2001

As a support analyst: remotely and on-site problem discovery/fixing in telecom/integration solutions. As a developer: coding/deploying POS embedded applications. System envs: SCO Unix, Slackware Linux, Windows NT 4, Verifone Omni/Verix. Software/Network envs: K&R C, Shell, SNA and TCP protocols.

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil **Computer Science Laboratory Administrator**

(Public University) 1996-1998

In charge of installing & maintaining the four computer labs in Computer Science school. System environments: Windows NT 3.51/4.0 workstations, Slackware Linux servers and workstations, Windows 95 workstations, AIX (workstations), Novell (servers). Network envs: TCP/IP, Netware, NetBEUI.

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil **Weather Sciences Laboratory Administrator**

(Public University)

1995

2001-2006

In charge of installing, maintaing and administering Meteorology labs in Geociences department. System environments: AIX, Windows 95/NT 3.51. Software/Network environments: Apache, Sendmail, TCP/IP.

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Programmer, Consultant and Instructor

(Public University) 1987-1995

For the academic community, as a programmer and internal consultant: application/system devel & consulting in C, Fortran and Pascal. As an administrator: PDP-11 (Unix), VAX 11/780 (VMS), EBC-32010 (Unix) systems administrator. As an instructor: C, 8086 Assembly, Unix System, VAX/VMS System.

Apoio Microinformática Ltda./Teledata, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Telecom Integration Solutions) Systems Programmer and Embedded Systems Developer

Systems and applications programming in C for HP-UX Unix platform. Embedded programming in C and Assembly for Ichtus MT-01 POS (8051) platform.

Módulo Consultoria e Informática Ltda., Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Security Software) **Systems Programmer** 1986

Low level systems programming (software protection) in 8086 Assembly and C, on MS-DOS environments.

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil **Computer Operator**

(Public University)

1985

Operation and administration for PDP-11 (Unix V6), VAX-11/780 and 8810 (VMS) systems.

Education

Computer Science, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro Electronics Engineering, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro Electronics Technician, Federal Center for Technical Education of Rio de Janeiro	(1985) (1982)